

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Startup Investments M&A Transactions Exit / Carve-Outs Value Creation Business Planning Valuations Technology

PERSONAL SKILLS

Hard-working
Dedicated
Reliable and professional
Organized
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated

INTERESTS

Football Hiking Surfing Sustainability Travel

CONTACT

19. Februar 1993 Zurich, Switzerland +41 79 378 23 83 samira_eilinger@hotmail.com Linkedin: <u>Samira Eilinger</u> Github: <u>samirajil</u>

SAMIRA EILINGER

INVESTMENTS, STARTUPS

ABOUT

I have 5 years of experience working as a portfolio manager in a corporate environment and collected extensive know-how in startup investments, M&A transactions and value creation for portfolio companies.

Currently learning more hands-on startup skills attending a 9-week intensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Ruby on Rails and complementing this with additional online courses in the field of online marketing, user experience and gamification.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TX GROUP | VENTURES DEPARTMENT
Senior Portfolio Manager | May 2019 - Jul 2020

- Development of new investment strategy
- Board of director responsibility for multiple portfolio companies
- Recruiting and managing Junior Portfolio Manager

Portfolio Manager | Jan 2017 - May 2019

- Close collaboration with portfolio CEOs regarding strategic initiatives, pricing and M&A opportunities to create value
- Project lead for different M&A transactions (buy and sell-side)

Startup Scout | Mar 2016 - Jan 2017

- Source investment opportunities, communicate with startups
- Project lead for divestment project and suport in other M&A projects

SWISS CAPITAL ALTERNATIVE INVESTMENTS

Working Student | May 2014 - May 2015

- Data collection for in-house hedge fund platform
- Administrative and organizational tasks for senior management team

EDUCATION

MASTER OF ARTS, BANKING AND FINANCE

University of Zurich | 2015-2017 University of Technology Sydney | 2017 (Exchange Semester)

BACHELOR OF ARTS, BANKING AND FINANCE

University of Zurich | 2011 - 2015

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Le Wagon | 2020



PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Startup Investments M&A Transactions Exit / Carve-Outs Value Creation Business Planning Valuations Technology Contract Negotiation

PERSONAL SKILLS

Hard-working
Dedicated
Reliable and professional
Organized
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated

INTERESTS

Football Hiking Surfing Sustainability Travel

CONTACT

19. Februar 1993 Zurich, Switzerland +41 79 378 23 83 samira_eilinger@hotmail.com Linkedin: <u>Samira Eilinger</u> Github: <u>samirajil</u>

SAMIRA EILINGER

INVESTMENTS, STARTUPS

BOARD SEATS

Olmero AG, Zürich | Board Seat | Oct 2019 - Jul 2020

Helpling Switzerland AG, Zürich | Board Seat | Jun 2019 - Jul 2020

Meekan, Tel Aviv | Board Seat | Jun 2019 - Jul 2020

Doodle AG, Zürich | Observer Seat | Mar 2017 - Jul 2020

Picstars AG, Zürich | Observer Seat | Sep 2017 - Jul 2020

Starticket AG, Zürich | Observer Seat | Mar 2017 - Dec 2019

DEAL SHEET (SELECTION)

renovero.ch | Carve-out Asset Deal | Apr 2020

- Digital services, exit of TX Group / Olmero AG to Swisscom
- Full M&A responsibility

Starticket AG | Share Deal | Dec 2019

- Digital media industry, exit of TX Group to Seetickets
- Full M&A responsibility

Magine TV | Asset Deal | Jan 2019

- Digital media industry, acquired by Zattoo
- M&A project lead in close collaboration with the Zattoo management

Helpling AG | Joint Venture | Oct 2018

- Digital services, JV with Helpling International (Rocket Internet)
- Investment and ongoing portfolio management responsibility

Zattoo International AG | Share Deal | Aug 2018

- Digital media industry, investment & buy-out of minority shareholders
- M&A and ongoing portfolio management responsibility
- Project lead for competition commission procedures

Picstars AG | Investment | Aug 2018

- Digital media industry, investment (lead investor)
- Investment and ongoing portfolio management responsibility

Tradono & Trendsales | Merger | Oct 2017

- Digital marketplaces, merger
- Support in business planing, synergy calculations and valuation

Hotelcard | Share Deal | Dec 2016

- Digital services, exit of TX Group to investors
- Project lead for company valuation and contract negotation